PROFILE

Skilled sound designer and music composer with extensive experience enhancing visual narratives through precise audio editing, sound design, and mixing of ambient soundscapes for various multimedia productions. Proficient in DAWs such as Pro Tools and Ableton Live, as well as various audio equipment for track recording, editing, and mixing. As a musician, I communicate clearly with clients to facilitate successful projects.

Additionally, I have a solid understanding of general administrative duties, including scheduling, record keeping, and office management. I hold a valid driver's license and am available for travel and commuting.



+44 7424305344



amandasweta@gmail.com



B24 8PP, Birmingham, UK



<u>Portfolio</u>

Linkedin

SKILLS

- DAWs: Ableton Live, Pro Tools, Logic Pro, Cycling '74 Max 8
- Software: REW, SketchUp, Illustrator
- Programming Languages: MATLAB, Max MSP, Pure Data
- Middleware & Game Engines: FMOD (basic), Unity (basic)
- Audio for Video: Synchronization, Video Alignment
- Web Development: HTML, CSS
- Musical Instruments: Electronic Keyboard, Guitar, Ukulele, Piano, Vocals
- Proficiency in Microsoft Office and data input applications

EDUCATION

BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION (MAXIMUS UK) 12-Week Course, 2024

Developed skills in administrative tasks, communication, and time management relevant to business environments

BSC. (HONS) MUSIC TECHNOLOGY

Birmingham City University (2019 -2023)

SECONDARY SCHOOL

Fr. Agnel Multipurpose School (2012-2019)

EXPERIENCE

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE (FIERCE FESTIVAL)

Birmingham, October 2024

- Provided excellent customer service by managing ticket scanning and guiding attendees, ensuring smooth event entry.
- Also, ensured a flawless experience while collaborating with the setup team to enhance operational efficiency demonstrating strong communication and teamwork skills.

FREELANCE - SOUND DESIGNER/COMPOSER

Birmingham (hybrid) 01/2023- Present

 Collaborated with producers and clients to create sound design and soundscapes for projects

ASSISTANT SOUND ENGINEER (PROJECT PARTICIPANT)

Birmingham City University 09/2022 - 01/2023

- Prepared for recording sessions by selecting and setting up microphones.
- Regulated volume level and sound quality during recording sessions.
- Developed strong communication and organisational skills through group projects.

PROJECTS

- Recording Sessions: Enhanced audio quality and contributed to seamless production flow by collaborating with musicians and sound engineers during a 3-year degree course.
- FPP Shooter Game: Designed immersive audio environment in collaboration with a developer and fellow sound designers.
- Tangled Movie Clip Sound Re-Design-Implemented 5.1 surround sound, focusing on spatialisation and ambience.
- NIME Project: Created 'Voice-Rec-Looper' interactive system using Max 8 (<u>link</u>).
- Personal Projects: '<u>Dreaming SouL</u>' and '<u>euphoriq</u>' electronic music artist projects

<u>ACCOMPLISHMENTS</u>

- Public Speaking: Represented high school in elocution, spelling bee, bard, and general knowledge competitions, achieving podium finishes (2014-2016).
- Academic Achievements: Consistent top performance as school topper with high grades.
- Elocution Competition: Won 1st place at the higher secondary level with a rolling trophy.
- Stage Performance: Demonstrated musical talent through performances on stage, including playing electronic keyboard, singing, and contributing to church choir.

DAW CERTIFICATION

Avid Pro Tools: Pro Tools 101(Jan 2022)

MUSIC CERTIFICATION

Completed Grades 1 to 5 in Music Theory and Keyboard practical through Trinity College London with distinction in each (2014-2019)

LANGUAGE

English Portuguese Hindi

References available upon request

WILLING TO RELOCATE*